Hey Jennifer.
Yes.
Uh freedom caucus friends showing up
tonight?
Like Steve Johnson gave me
>> Mr. Mr. Rainey, you're on the
microphone, sir.
Recording in progress.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I'd
like to call the April 13th meeting of
the governing body to order and ask the
clerk to take the roll, please. Mr.
Wolfe.
Here.
Dr. Aldrich. Here. Mayor Collins.
Dr. Emmons. Present. Mr. Escobedo. Here.
Mr. Laybourn. Here. Mr. Moody. Here. Dr.
Rinne.
Present. Mr. Seagrave. Present. Mr.
White.
>> Present. All members are present. We do
have a quorum. Would you please join me
in the pledge of allegiance?
Consent agenda. All agenda items listed
with the designation of CA are
considered to be routine items by the
governing body and will be enacted by
one motion. There will be no separate
discussion on these items unless a
member of the governing body so requests
and support by two other members is
received. Any item removed from the
consent agenda will be considered in its
normal sequence on the agenda.
All right. Are there any items a member
of the governing body would like to
remove from the consent agenda? Mr.
Mayor.
Mr. Laybourn.
Item 22.
Concur.
That item That item deals with the uh
the sidewalks, so we'll remove item 22.
Yes.
Mr. Mayor. Yes, sir.
Item 31C.
That has to do with our city's audit.
Concur. Concur.
Okay.
I'd ask if somebody would please remove
item 21. Um there's nothing wrong with
it. It just happens to uh be on the
consent agenda. We have to approve the
zoning before we can do the So moved.
Concur. Concur.
All right. Well, I move item 21 also.
Any others?
Hearing none, I would entertain a
motion.
So moved. Second.
All right. All those in favor of the
consent agenda with items 21, 22, and
31C being removed, please signify by
saying I. I. Those opposed? The consent
agenda is approved.
Number 7A, public hearing to determine
whether compliance of annexation
conditions requested by Wyoming Statute
15-1-402
exists for about 1,259.91
acres of land located west of Roundtop
Road and adjacent to Happy Jack Road.
Before I go to Mr. White for a staff
report, apparently we had a little uh
um heart-raising incident earlier today.
When Ms. Black and Mr. Cox um
saw that their names were on this
annexation
um ordinance, and that came because we
had a 40-some acres that were uh
were brought into the
um
into this, but this the county had not
updated their maps yet. And so, when our
staff pulled that across, uh the Cox
Ranch LLC was put on there. Since then,
we fixed all of those documents, and I
apologize to them for causing their
heart rate to go up just a little bit
today. And with that being said, we'll
go to our staff for a quick staff
report.
Mayor, members of the council, Connor
White, Planning and Development
Department.
The annexation
uh this annexation is for roughly
1,259.91
acres of land generally generally
located west of Roundtop Road and
adjacent to Happy Happy Jack Road.
Uh this is an owner land basically an
owner petitioned annexation. Um so, the
owner land is the larger portion on the
north side of Happy Jack and the little
bit that extends down into North Range
Business Park.
The city does have land within this
annexation that we tied into it. Uh it's
just the water
um treatment plant out there. BOPU was
looking to annex that in the near
future. Uh this annexation came up, and
they asked if they could just add that
into the annexation um and move this
along as well. But, the original
annexation petition is landowner
petitioned
um for the land to be annexed.
Uh that petition was filed with the city
clerk on February 17th, 2026. The
petition was certified by the city clerk
as containing the necessary signatures
according to state statute on February
uh 17th, 2026.
Public hearing is being held in
accordance with Wyoming State Statute
15-1-402A.
Pursuant to fulfilling the requirements
of state statute, staff asks the
governing body to consider the
following.
The land proposed to be annexed is
contiguous to city limits, specifically
uh the property is 5.26%
contiguous.
All city services and utilities
currently available to residents of the
city would be provided to the residents
of the annexed land. Extending water and
sewer will increase the health, safety,
and welfare of this area of the
community.
The area to be annexed is partly inside
the urban service boundary and
designated with urban transition
residential
um or has no designation
by the future land use map. Uh I should
note there is a proposed future land use
map amendment that will be coming
forward for this project as well uh that
will be introduced in 2 weeks.
This type of development is best
supported by being within city limits
and connecting to city services.
Certified mailing was sent to all
landowners and utilities within the
annexed area not less than 20 business
days prior to the public hearing.
According to the city's calendar, 20
business days prior to tonight's hearing
was March 16th, 2026.
The certified mailing was sent on March
13th, 2026, and the earliest confirmed
receipt was dated March 16th, 2026. And
then, property owners within 300 ft of
the area to be annexed
uh were also mailed public notice within
that same time period.
Uh this annexation is accompanied by a
signed zoning ordinance as well. Uh and
there is also a proposed zone change for
the uh landowner petitioned area
that will also run along concurrent with
the annexation. And then, as I
mentioned, the future land use map
amendment will be introduced in 2 weeks
and will basically have final reading
the same night as all the other
ordinances, so everything
runs together.
With that, I am available for any
questions.
Thank you. Any questions from staff or
for from for our staff from the
governing body?
Easy for me to say. [snorts]
Dr. Aldrich. Mayor Collins, uh through
you,
can you tell us how many residents
reside in this
property that's going to be annexed or
is being proposed to be annexed?
>> Mayor, through you,
uh to my knowledge, none.
Uh the land is completely vacant is my
understanding, and then we've got the
water treatment plant, which the city
owns. Otherwise, there are no residences
within
that area.
Follow up, Dr. Aldrich? Yes, follow up.
Um does this include any of the area
that we would refer to as Camp Carefree,
the Girl Scout camp that is um
by the old water treatment facility? It
runs, I think, to the
I would think that's the north, sorry. I
think it's the north of it. Mm. Mayor,
through you, that I
Okay.
So, it sounds like it is not. I heard
somebody, possibly one of the Yeah.
So, it sounds like it's not. I wouldn't
know to my knowledge, but um my
understanding is this is
vacant land. Okay, thank you.
Any other questions for staff? Yeah.
Mr. Moody. Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor,
through you. Uh thank you, sir. Um
how many residents are within, say, half
a mile of this annexation?
Mayor, through you,
maybe a
just a couple within a half a mile. I
didn't measure the exact distance from
the closest corner. Um Um
But they aren't within the 300-ft notice
radius.
Follow me, Mr. Mayor. Sir.
Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Mayor, through
you.
Um my other question is the other the
residential area, I know is county. Are
there plans that they annex them as
well?
Mayor, through you.
There is no plans for the city to do any
initiated annexations out in this area.
Again, this is a landowner petition
annexation. This is not city initiated.
Yes, the city is planning to annex its
own land out in this area, but we are
not initiating the annexation of the
1,000 roughly 1,100 and I think it's 95
acres.
Um but there's
this area isn't 100% surrounded by city
limits. There's no plans at this time to
do any city initiated annexations out in
this direction. Mr. Moody, follow? I'm
good. Thank you. Mr. Wolf?
Um thank [clears throat] you, Mr. Mayor,
uh through you. Um
thank you for the presentation. What's
the proposed uh use of the annexed land?
Mayor, through you. So, I don't know if
I have a proposed use. Um my
understanding is a business park.
Uh so, the zoning map amendment that
will come later is not part of this
discussion particularly, but will be on
the agenda moving forward is a zone
change to business park zoning. Uh the
future land use map uh request was to
mixed-use employment.
And my understanding from our discussion
at planning commission, it would be a
business park, like a full business
park, like North Range Business Park.
Uh
could you just sort of describe
the next steps that will occur after
this public hearing and the timing of
those, please?
I'm sorry, Mr. Mayor, through you. Mr.
White. Mayor, through you. So, after
this public hearing, um all the
ordinances except for the future land
use map amendment will be introduced
tonight and referred to public service
committee.
So, then next Monday, all those items,
basically annexation, assigned zoning,
and the zoning map amendment will be
discussed at public service next Monday.
They will then go on to second reading
in front of the full governing body
um
following Monday after that. And that is
where the introduction for the future
land use map will also be introduced and
referred to public service committee.
Then those, as long as everything is
approved, will still move on to uh
public service committee the Monday
after.
And then
all four items will be discussed at
public service committee, and then all
four items would move on to third
reading uh
the Monday after that. Um I should note
that at just for council
um and also our city clerk and probably
attorney to know that we probably will
have to um kind of change the rules of
order and pull the future land use map
off and have that considered because it
is a resolution. It will need to be
considered prior to the zoning map
amendment, but after the annexation and
assigned zoning.
>> [snorts]
>> So, we'll have to move a few things
around to get those in order because the
the zone change is dependent on the
future land use map amendment.
Uh
Mr. Wolf. Mr. Mayor, follow up through
you. Thank you.
Um so, at at what point in this process
do we have a discussion about what the
benefit is to the city of annexing this
property?
Mayor, through you. That would
be probably next Monday and the Mondays
after through the process.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Anybody else in the governing body?
All right, Mr. White, thank you. Now,
folks,
I don't know how many of you
have been to one of our meetings before,
but I thought maybe I would just kind of
go through how we do this. Um we're so
excited to see people here. Um we have
two microphones. If you'll just come up
to these microphones, push the button
and the green light will come on. Uh
please introduce yourself clearly so our
clerk can know who you are, and you'll
have 3 minutes to address the governing
body. So, with that, we'll go to Mr.
White.
Uh Michael White, through you, Mr.
Mayor.
Um
couple comments I'd like to make uh
Mr. Wolf, Mr. Moody brought up the fact
of the landowners.
Well, let's make sure we understand that
the property
to the east of the Cox land is also
owned by the one of the family members.
Um and if I said that wrong, they can
correct me. Number two, uh at the
planning commission, I asked the fact
that
um
Connor White said there was two parcels
and two owners.
I felt like
each parcel should have been
independent. Um
the parcel for the city water treatment
plant
should have been brought separately
because the owner is actually the
public.
The next point I'd like to make is like
um Councilman Wolf brought
what benefit it is. Um
And I'm not sure what the benefit it is,
except I'm assuming the business park's
going to need uh
stuff from the Board of Public
Utilities. The next point I'd like to
make is that uh
who's going to be the um ultimate person
to do the fire service. Um right now, we
have a
new county fire station at the
intersection of Roundtop and uh Happy
Jack. Does that change? If it does, it's
going to probably be past the
5 miles where you get a decent uh
response time. So, these are questions
that I had, and I appreciate Connor
White's uh
expertise on this.
I somewhat
think that everything hasn't been
pre-presented tonight where I guess
Councilman Wolf made the point that uh
through the city that we could address
that at the next meeting, but uh
I
think that uh we should get everybody
the opportunity to voice their opinion,
and thank you.
Anyone else like to speak to us? Mr.
Galliotis, welcome.
Uh good evening.
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh Sam Galliotis, 8827 Shellback Road,
Cheyenne, Wyoming.
Um honorable mayor and esteemed council
members, I echo many of the questions
that have already been asked regarding
this.
Uh for point of reference, um
I represent the property entirely on the
west side of this large chunk of land
and to the north side of it.
Um I I would just as a
for the record,
uh for something that's sensitive as
this, I was pleased to learn that uh
there was a name snafu on the
application and the information, but
that caused, you know, those of us who
have limited time
to look into these things, uh putting
false information out or incorrect
information
is a little bit frustrating. And I think
for a body such as this, it should be
of much higher quality.
Um my questions really surround
why do you think this fits?
I mean, Happy Jack Road on the on the
south side of it is all industry and uh
industrial and everything else, and
everything on the on the north side of
Happy Jack doesn't fit into that.
You have a huge housing development just
to the east. I am curious about the the
piece of land that's separating the two
and why those property owners weren't
really advised in what the intent of
that land is.
Um but you know, how does this fit into
what's going on there? There's nothing
industrial north of uh of Happy Jack
Road. And when I go through the
documents, um you know, my questions
would center center around the
beneficial use to the community. Um I'm
really have a big question about, and
I'd like these to be articulated if they
can, that it's compatible with the
surrounding area and the goals.
Uh and then when you look at the state
statutes, I'd really like uh you know,
the representatives here to articulate,
you know, how how is this a logical and
feasible addition to the annexing city
or town?
Because it doesn't seem logical or
feasible to me
where it's situated at,
the neighborhood it's in, and those
types of things. I would also ask for
somebody to articulate how it
constitutes a natural and geographic,
economical, and social part of the
annexing city. And when I looked at the
answers to some of these, they basically
just answer, like for example,
protection of the health, safety, and
welfare of the persons residing in the
area where there are no persons.
Um there's not a lot of persons around
it.
And it
uh when when I read the documents, it
basically says, "Well, it it's for the
protection, health, and safety of the
people and the residents." But it
doesn't articulate
the rationale at all on any of those
three points. So, um those are things
that I would like to learn about. Um
I'm a fairly progressive guy,
uh but it none of this fits into where
it's at right now.
And um I would really be interested in
this map that shows
just to the east of the subject
properties
and between the subject property and the
residential district of what's going to
happen with that land. Is that part of
this? Who owns it? What's the intent of
it? Um those would all be very important
questions. So, if you can answer any of
those, uh great. Otherwise, I can come
back and ask more. Thanks.
Thanks, Mr. Eliottis. Sir.
Mayor and Council, thank you very much.
Um I'm Barry Meyer at 7713
Barrington Road.
And I also have family that that could
not make it at 8607 Cox Road. We're just
concerned about how it's going to affect
us. We we were so close on the map right
there.
Like with taxes, we're also looking at
like it's just so close with traffic and
that. And we're also worried that maybe
we could be annexed in the future. Um
really like where we're at. All the the
you know, all the fans came up and you
know, kind of ruined the
the the the mountains and that. And I
just don't like to see another building
come up, you know, where they'll just
ruin the mountains and that. So,
personally, that's where I'm coming
from. And I just wanted to speak my um
my side. Thank you very much for your
time.
>> it. Appreciate you being here tonight.
Thank you.
Mr. Love.
Mr. Mayor, members of the Council.
Uh took a little reprieve from our last
couple of meetings, but I'm back. Um
I just have a few couple a couple of
questions.
>> yourself to start with, right?
>> Oh, I'm Steven Love. Uh I live in Ward
1.
Um
I have a couple of questions for Connor,
if that's okay. Through you, Mr. Mayor.
Um I was just curious what um the
requirements for upgrades, like uh
especially roads and boat who would be.
Um it was made pretty clear that if the
Nicely's want to do anything with their
land, um they would have to upgrade, put
in a deceleration lane and whatnot. I
was just curious what the uh
expectations for this particular
property were. Mr. Love, I don't
remember that being a condition of their
being able to be a farmer. Sorry, not I
I'm sorry if I was unclear. A condition
if they wanted to uh expand their
business on their property.
>> Not not true, either. Um I know that was
the narrative that was put out by the
public, but not the narrative that came
from us.
So, I apologize, sir, but I don't agree
with your premise. So, Mr. Mayor, if I
don't mean to argue with me you
apologize, but if they wanted more than
25 people a day, they wouldn't have to
put in an deceleration lane. Is that
correct?
>> that is correct. They do not have to put
a deceleration lane for that. If you
remember right, they had to have more
than it was a 10,000 cars a day, and
they were at 5,000 or 4,800 cars a day.
Um they don't expect that that would
happen until 2045 or something like
that, if maybe then. Um
so, again, that was the narrative that
was put out by a lot of people who stood
in here and talked to us, but if you
remember right, we tried to push back on
the narrative as not being accurate.
Okay, I'm sorry if that was my mis- a
misunderstanding. So, there won't be any
required upgrades for this property. Is
that what you're saying? Not if it stays
as a ranch. Now, if they want to do some
development on it, I'm sure that the
city engineer,
uh WYDOT, some other people might have
some requirements for them to do some
upgrades. But again, at this point, we
have no
we have no understanding what that might
be. So, you're saying as long as it
stays with that AG definition, Say that
again, sir.
>> As long as it stays with that AG
definition after you guys annex the
property, Yep. Or even if we change it
to a business park, as long as there's
no development, uh there's nothing that
would cause there to be an improvement.
Annexation does not cause a requirement
for improvements. Only what if you're
going to develop it to a point that um
those would become uh necessary by our
city engineer or um our city planners,
somebody else that would say, "In order
to be able to do that volume, you're
going to have to do these upgrades." And
again, because we don't know what that
is, we can't answer that question. Okay.
My other question, sorry, my last
question for you was um is there any um
is there any concern that there will be
the creation of pockets within the city,
not necessarily 100% contained within
the city, but that would require um
us going through essentially what we
went through previously.
You know, I think, Mr. Love, in a
perfect world, we would annex a nice
great squares. So, the city would grow
um
you know, in a really uniform way. But
that's not the way you do it in Wyoming.
We have uh
I guess the thought that people um
who want to be part of the city will
come and ask. And then eventually,
someday in the future, there may be some
pockets that start to have those
jurisdictional challenges that we've
been facing. Uh so, that could happen. I
think probably will happen again in the
future. Uh we're doing everything we can
to uh alleviate that. But um you know,
if one person annexes and the others
don't, you know, someday long time in
the future. I mean, it took us 150 years
to get the point where we were. Um it's
going to take a long time for that to
happen again. So, I guess just uh
clarify for my understanding, is that
how pockets get created? Cuz it's my
understanding that you guys aren't
legally allowed to. So, is it the
owner-initiated annexation that creates
those?
>> That's correct, sir.
>> I understand. Yep, exactly. Okay. Thank
you.
Thanks for being here again tonight.
Anybody else?
Please.
Good evening, ma'am.
If you could identify yourself for the
record, and hold that microphone right
in front of your face. Thank you.
Mayor,
members of the City Council, thank you.
My name is Carmen Cook. I reside at 3221
McKinney Drive, which is in Rolling
Hills Estates, which is east of the
proposed annexation.
I have a few questions. Uh
as far as what what when they annex
this, what are they talking about when
they talk about industrial? Are we
talking about putting in solar panels?
Are we talking about putting in more of
the tech centers? What what are they
talking about putting in there as far as
business is concerned?
Ma'am, if it's going to be a business
park zone change, I think um
maybe Connor or uh Charles, what would
be uh what would be allowed in a
business park zone change?
We're going to try to get you an answer,
ma'am. Thank you.
Mayor, through you.
So, in the business park zoning dis- uh
zone district, it does allow for data
centers, it allows for utility stations,
it allows for industrial light
industrial uses.
It allows for commercial uses as well.
Um so, it does allow gas stations, it
allows any of the commercial stuff. I
believe we allow hotels.
It business park zoning is meant to be a
mix of our commercial or community
business zone district, our light
industrial zone district, and a bit of
our heavy industrial zone district. So,
it has a very flexible kind of zoning
for that stuff. And Connor, if I
remember correctly, um it doesn't allow
you to have your impacts go beyond your
property lines, right? So, noise and um
and that type of stuff should be
mitigated towards the property line.
Correct, Mayor, through you. Uh that's
correct. Um
Basically, I believe we do prohibit our
like actual industrial uses when it does
create large
amounts of noise, fumes, smoke, odor,
all of that. Those are not allowed.
>> That would be in a heavy industrial use.
>> Yeah, that's basically our heavy
industrial zone district, but we left
those out of the business park zone
district. Did that help you, ma'am? So,
the solar parks and the tech centers are
not considered like is it light light
pollution or noise? My understanding
[clears throat] is that they create a
lot of noise, and they create a lot of
light pollution.
Connor, is a a solar farm considered in
a business park? Mayor, through you.
Your boss is nodding his head, yes.
Okay. Now, I'm going to go with what
he's
nodding. I was trying to think what we
we haven't really had one of those that
has come into the city where we've had
to evaluate that on what the
particular use is. Um but when it comes
to like a data center, if you want to
call that a tech center, yes, those are
allowed. Um but again, we have noise
restrictions on even those. So, if they
are producing past the property line,
they would end up jumping into our
industrial use category, which then
makes them not allowed.
Go ahead, ma'am.
>> Well, it's my understanding that the one
that they put out by
the Walmart distribution center, they
had to put a fence up because of the
noise. So, you know, us being so close
to that area, I I worry about the noise.
I don't live very far from there.
Carmen, it's something you should be
worried about, but we uh
we learned a lesson from that. That
wasn't a data center, but it was
actually a a bit mining operation. And
they assured us that they would be under
the the limits, but they have since then
changed all the fans, and we think
they're going to be in compliance this
year. And hopefully, the fences and
stuff can come down. We those fences
were temporary.
>> Hills. Are we going to be notified as to
what is going to go in there?
You know, as the as the uses go forward,
I don't know what the what the the
policy once they're zoned by right. I
don't think they're going to call and
and tell you what's going on, but we'll
try to make
>> are we actually don't have any say as to
what our neighbors are going to be.
I think that's fair, ma'am.
Thank you.
Mayor.
Mayor, can I ask a question?
>> Yeah, of course. Connor, sorry.
Oh. Sir, go ahead.
Connor, I just had a a quick question.
When did the owner of the land
uh request
this land to be annexed?
Do we have a date an approximate date on
that?
February 17th.
>> February. Or through you, it would have
been around February 17th, cuz
basically, once it's submitted to the
city,
I have to file that with the city
clerk's office uh for them to make sure
all the paperwork actually meets state
statute. And that is basically when it
starts the annexation process. So, I
want to say February 7th around February
17th. Okay, thank you.
Mr. Mayor,
Con- Mr. Mayor Conner, don't run.
Don't run away.
Mr. Wolf.
Um, thank you, Mayor, through you. Um,
maybe just for the benefit of the
public, um,
assuming all of the things that you
described in answer to my my prior
question occur,
all of the public service committee
meetings and
the zoning changes and this is all
approved, then we have a piece of land
annexed into the city with the type of
zoning that you've described. So, if
somebody wants to build a data center
there,
what other involvement would your office
have, um, in in the approval of that and
that and and also what would the
public's opportunity be, uh, to be
involved in that process? Mr. White.
Mayor, through you. So, looking at the
property site, everything that goes
through council at this point for this
land gets approved and it's annexed,
it's own business park, call it that.
Basically, what we'd be waiting for is a
site plan or unless they do The only
thing that would come back to the
governing body, I should say, would be
if they are to plat the property, create
lots, create streets,
and all of that, that would come back
before the governing body.
If it's just a site plan for a data
center,
um, that's basically administrative.
That goes through our office, we review
it to make sure it meets the unified
development code for all design
requirements, landscaping, parking
requirements, all of that.
The engineer department looks at
drainage, traffic. We look at how their
accesses work, traffic studies, drainage
studies.
Water public utilities would be looking
at, uh, water sewer connections, how
they're extending mains, where they're
getting those services from.
Um, fire department looks at it to make
sure it complies with all fire codes and
making sure that there's hydrants in the
area so that they can also operate out
there just in case there's a fire.
Trying to think of other departments
involved. There's
we have like 20 some odd reviewers when
it comes to site plans. So, it's hard to
remember everybody who's on it. Um, but
there's various city departments that go
into reviewing it, but there is no
public process. It's all at that point,
it's a permitted use.
And it just has to meet, uh, the adopted
zoning code at that point.
Follow up, Mr. Wolf. Uh, thank you, Mr.
Mayor, through you. And so, all through
that site plan process, then, is there
any notice provided to the residents or
the the nearby neighbors about what what
you're doing and what you plan to do as
you review this? Mayor, through you. No,
there would be no notice. Um,
we do have a website for putting
projects up. I haven't been putting data
centers up specifically because a lot of
times
that's we don't put up their documents.
Um,
they're kind of a little confidential in
some cases when it comes to the data
center documents.
Um,
but there is a website that we have,
Connect Cheyenne. Uh, it does allow for
us to put up projects.
Um, and that's not necessarily
notification. Uh, it does allow people
to see what's going on throughout the
city.
Um,
but there's no mailed notice. It doesn't
go through a public process. There's no
discussion. It's basically the city
reviews it,
making sure it meets all the required
codes. Okay. So, Mr. Mayor, uh, just one
follow up, if I might.
Um, thank you. Uh, through um,
so, if
the residents are worried about a data
center or a solar farm
or
Bitcoin mining operations,
really
am I correct that their really only
opportunity is to be involved in this
process that you described for the next
few weeks,
um,
uh, and to express their opinions as Mr.
Galliotis, um, did and and others have
and express their concerns about it. And
those concerns are really directed just
to the question of whether or not
the property ought to be annexed. Is it
Isn't Is that how that works? Mayor,
through you. No, because there is the
zoning map amendment, also.
So, the zoning map amendment is a
separate ordinance from the annexation.
That is what actually defines what the
zoning is.
So, we have the annexation of the land.
So, council can choose to either annex
the land or not. If you don't annex the
land, then the other ordinances don't
matter. If you do annex the land,
then there's the assigned zoning.
The recommended assigned zoning with
this project is AG for the
uh, landowner petitioned.
The city, we're recommending P public
for our parcel.
Um, but otherwise, the AG would be the
assigned zoning.
And then there's the future land use map
amendment.
And then there's the zone change
request from the landowner to business
park.
So, the zoning is what would allow those
uses. So, council could still annex the
property, still assign it the AG zone,
but then not give it the business park
zone district.
And then it's stuck in the AG zone.
Or council could just not annex the land
and then the other
ordinances don't matter, as I said, but
um, basically, the zoning the zone
change is where probably those concerns
about use should be brought up
cuz that is what basically allows those
uses with the zoning map amendment.
Also, I guess the future land use map
amendment because that is basically what
would allow the zone change to go
forward.
So, those would be the two items I would
say have to deal with use of the land
and what possibilities there are for
that land.
And and Mr. Mayor, I apologize, Mr.
Wolf. Um,
thank you. This is very helpful. Uh,
and so,
um,
the zone change from AG,
agriculture, to
business use
could occur sometime in the future.
Mr. Wolf, it's actually going to happen
simultaneously with annexation. Yeah,
Mayor, through you. That is an item that
is being introduced tonight along with
the annexation and will go through the
three readings with the annexation, so
concurrently. The only item that is
delayed by 2 weeks is the resolution for
the future land use map amendment.
Just so everything lines up cuz
resolutions only need two readings.
Thank you very much. Thank you, Mayor.
Hi. Anybody else for Mr. Moody?
Thank you, Mr. Mayor, through you. I
said, uh, one question my colleague
asked and and you answered, uh,
Mr. White. Um, you said the data centers
don't have any documentation at all,
it's all redacted. Is it like that for
all the other businesses in business
park, like Magpul and all that, or is it
just the data centers?
Mayor, through you.
The documents aren't redacted,
okay, but I do know the city has been
asked to not always post those
documents. I can probably and I can let
Charles fill in. We can post a site
plan,
but I think they're more concerned about
the internal building functions.
Mr. Bloom, do you want to follow up on
that? Yes, Mayor, members of council,
Charles Bloom, planning development
director. Um, with our site plans, we do
generally have those online with
documentation. There's some proprietary
elements of their site plans that we are
obligated not to share that are that are
in industry specific items that
these folks give themselves different
competitive advantage with other folks.
So, those ones are the items that we do
not post online, but generally, we will
have the item out there, so people are
able to see the site plans that are are
available, but if there is proprietary
information on there, we work with the
applicants to ensure that that is not,
um, on public display.
You have more thoughts? Yeah. Uh,
I just saw your I just saw your
microphone's on. I know. I I I I have
some questions for Mr. Bloom. Okay. Uh,
when I might.
Dr. Aldridge. Mayor Collins, through
you. I have, um, three or four questions
here. One is, can you remind me, um,
Conner or Charles, what is the zone that
would allow man camps?
Uh, Mayor, through you. There there is
no zone that allows man camps. We've
deleted that from the unified
development code. The only thing we have
now is RV campgrounds,
but those even have kind of higher
standards. So, we don't have a zone
district that allows man camps. Those
are completely deleted.
>> that completely.
Okay. Mayor, through you Dr. Aldridge, I
just like to add on real quick to that.
We do have a mechanism to allow for
alternative housing arrangements. Um, it
would be through our planned unit
development process. That process would
have a significant neighborhood
meetings, um, at the beginning. It would
have a multiple rounds of consideration
by the governing body, earlier round of
consideration by the planning
commission, but we do have an avenue to
allow some type of housing. However, it
would have to be very detailed and it
would have a lot of public involvement
and involvement at the governing body
level.
Dr. Aldridge, I feel like we're getting
a little bit away from the purpose of
the public hearing here. Um, do you have
any questions specific to the public
hearing? Go ahead.
>> I wanted to, um, ask if the information
now has been corrected on our website,
um,
that was erroneous. Mayor, through you.
Not yet. I
didn't realize it was incorrect until
this afternoon, like an hour before this
meeting.
So, I've started
going through and correcting everything.
Um, so, once I get the stamped
ordinances back, I'm going to create all
new council packets and kind of redo
all the documents I had that had the
name in there. And my last question,
Mayor, through you, is my understanding
is that the only way to
really control if you will
property that's annexed or maybe next to
your property is to actually purchase
that property. Is that correct?
Mayor through you that's kind of a good
way to put it is if you want to control
the land you need to own the land. Thank
you.
Sir, go ahead.
Please come forward.
Would you identify yourself for the
record please?
Paul Kremples I'm at 2606 McKinney
Drive. Thank you for just a quick bit of
your time.
And I understand the concept of if you
want to control the land you got to own
the land
but many of us have been out there for
many many years. I know we've been there
for 40 years
plus many of my neighbors have been
there and
I agree with Mr. Galeotas that this is
not a fit. A business park
there
adjacent to a residential area plus it
creates a pocket that you'll have to
deal with later on or we will have to
deal with later on that
that you're dealing with those issues
right now.
Um Mr. Kremples I don't see a pocket. I
apologize. Well, I think you will see a
pocket. If you look at that map you'll
find that Rolling Hills now is now
surrounded
to the base to the east
Front Range Business Park to the south
and now you would have this other
business park to the west. Um
It's just a matter of time before I
start going hmm
Do we want to
start looking at that piece of property
and
to those to those residential areas.
It's coming and you know it. And to that
I object. We've been there we live in
Wyoming for a reason. We we like the
lifestyle.
We put up with the weather. We put up
with a lot of stuff
to live here and to have somebody else
come in and
I'm sorry.
>> Especially the wind lately.
>> Especially the wind.
>> Yes, sir. Especially to the west side of
the of the city. So
that's my point is
I think you do will end up with a
a pocket but I think it is a is a bad
fit for
those of us that have lived out there
for many many years.
Good to have you here. Thank you. Thank
you. Sir.
Mr. Mayor Council Rick Kessler 3605
Burke Drive.
I just have a question that I'm not sure
was answered that Mr. Galeotas asked.
If you look at the map and
see what the land uses where the
annexation is going to take place.
Everything
east of Rolling Hills
and to the north is all ranch land.
So the question I have is that I'm not
sure was answered is that it says the
urban development of the area sought to
be annexed would constitute a natural
geographical economical and social part
of the annexing city or town. So my
question is how does that happen if if
most of the property to the north and
east of Rolling Hills is ranch land. So
I would like to see if if you could
enlighten me on that part. Thank you.
Anybody else that would like to uh
to speak?
Hi, my name is Minda Blevins. I live at
>> Sorry, I didn't catch your name. Minda
Blevins.
I live in the Rolling Hills neighborhood
and I live at 7814 Cox Road. I just kind
of want to reiterate what a lot of our
neighbors have have been saying and I
want to kind of add a couple of things.
Thank you Mr. Mayor and Council. I
apologize. Wasn't planning on speaking.
It was incredibly stressful obviously to
think that it was our neighborhood and
then to come tonight and realize that it
was not because I know a lot of us were
scrambling trying to reach out to each
other and you know in this day and age
it's very hard to accommodate things
when you've got families and you're
trying to accommodate all of those
things. So it was a little comforting to
hear that that is not in fact happening.
It's still very concerning though.
My husband was military for 20 years. We
chose to move back here. Neither my
husband or I are from here but when he
was stationed here we loved it. We love
this area. When we looked to buy
property we knew we where we wanted to
buy and living out on that side of town
is an absolute amazing opportunity. I
can't tell you how many times that I sit
out on my back patio and I have my
coffee and I just enjoy the quiet the
peace the the wildlife is something no
one has really mentioned as well
between that property that neighborhood
and Curt Gowdy we have lots of wildlife.
That is concerning to me to think about
what another business
park would do in that area. I'm also
concerned with
the fact that traffic. I don't know if
you don't live in that neighborhood you
may not realize when I-80 shuts down our
neighborhood is absolutely horrendous to
get in and out and having had teenage
drivers trying to come out onto Happy
Jack from that neighborhood it is very
problematic and very nerve-racking. And
when we look at the number of times that
I-80 is shut down because of the weather
those semis block that up. We're going
to add traffic to that which is very
concerning to me and I wonder if that's
been something that considered. And then
I'm also fearful of what happens next.
If that annexes what about the property
if we continue to go out what's going to
happen next? I I would hate to think
that we would be kind of blocked in by
all of these business all these
businesses that potentially are going to
ruin the residential areas. And like I
said we all purchased properties out
there for a reason. We love the Wyoming
wildlife. We love the neighborhood. We
love the peace and quiet and I would
hate to lose that and kind of be buried
with all different kinds of businesses.
Um thank you. I appreciate that. Thanks
for being here.
Sam you can't have two times. Come on
now.
You know I'm just teasing you. So so I I
I think it's all of these questions are
very pertinent.
And
but just listening for the people who
were kind of be led to believe that
there's a process that's going to be
time before all of this these decisions
are made
frankly it's all happening right now.
I mean if we're if we're being straight
about it and Sam
Sam no decisions are being made tonight.
It's a public hearing.
>> no I mean if if you annex everything
else is stacked up it's going to happen
at the same time. All of that. And I I
understand through
you know many conversations with city
people
your desire to annex more property and
tax base and everything else. I get
that. But I go back to this is not
congruent with the area. Totally get
what's happened south of of Happy Jack
Road. It's industrial. It's been that
way. You know you go out further you got
the landfill all of that but north of it
this does not fit. So I I go back to the
question I asked and Mr. Kessler asked
is
so what's the rationale? How is this a
fit and what's the cost the city of
Cheyenne to annex this and by the way I
don't even know who the petitioner is
now.
I haven't seen that. Um
and lastly answer that question. It was
signed by Joe Cox
who is a trustee of the William Cox
William S. Cox Revocable Trust. That's
who is asking for the annexation. Okay.
And then the last thing I I would like
to hear an answer on the land
immediately to the east of the proposed
annexation property but sandwiched
between
Rolling Hills and this proposed
annexation.
It what cuz it's you're changing the use
there and what's that all about? I'd
like to understand that. Thank you.
Conner do you want to talk is the land
use amendment that we'll be seeing here
in the near future a couple weeks from
now?
I was going to pull the map back up but
the land that's directly east that
wasn't in the yellow area that is
basically it's a parcel between Rolling
Hills and this parcel. That is not part
of the annexation. That's not part of
the future land use map amendment.
That's not part of the zone change. That
property has nothing to do with this
annexation. That's being left in the
county.
Nothing's changing with it to my
knowledge.
The only thing we're discussing is what
was highlighted.
That was petitioned for annexation.
So to be clear that the land that's in
between the the annexed area and the
neighborhood there is no changes in land
use zoning any any parts of it. Mayor
through you that is correct. Not at
least in the city. I don't There could
be things going on in the county. But
it's not part of this and it's not going
through city processes to change
anything. Thank you, sir.
Do you have somebody online?
Mr. Smith you should be able to unmute
yourself.
Mr. Smith.
Mr. Smith we can't hear you.
Mr. Smith you just muted yourself again.
Now you're unmuted.
Sir.
Mr. Smith, you just need to unmute
yourself and speak. We'll listen to you.
Well, why don't we take Ms. Woodhouse
and maybe we can come back to Mr. Smith,
uh Jennifer, when you can
Ms. Woodhouse.
Good evening, Mr. Mayor and members of
the City Council. Gay Woodhouse, 1912
Capital Avenue. I am here
uh on behalf of Cox Ranches LLC. Uh and
we do appreciate uh we understand that
it was basically a clerical error that
included them as the applicant and the
owner of these parcels. We understand
how that happened based on the website
not being changed after a transfer of
some of the property that's included in
this, but uh we do have another issue,
and there are a couple that have come to
mind for me since we've started.
One of them is you are creating you are
creating a pocket. You know, the pocket
between Rolling Hills and this is now is
now a pocket. It's a large pocket. And
then just to the north is ran is land
that Cox Ranches still owns
uh that goes up beyond Rolling Hills and
over uh to the Round Top Road. So,
they're going to be part of that pocket
as well. So, I can understand the
concern of people who are going to be in
a pocket and possibly go through what
we've just seen in in some other
annexations occurring lately.
One of the one of the primary
issues with Cox Ranches LLC and Beverly
Black and her husband Gordon Black are
here to have me express this is
they have a mausoleum
where their all their ancestors have
been buried that's up on the top of the
hill. You can see it from Happy Jack
Road when you go there. That is part of
on part of this property.
And if it's a data center you know, they
move dirt like I don't I it's just hard
to imagine what could possibly happen to
their mausoleum
as this moves forward and whether or not
it's protected, whether or not they're
able to have access to it. I mean,
that's a major major concern for them
and we need that what they really
weren't aware of this till tonight. So,
uh we're going to be doing some work as
well, but it's a horrible
thought that that mausoleum could be
removed or
certainly the access could be denied.
>> Ms. Woodhouse, you're saying on the the
area the land being annexed, the
mausoleum is on that part of the ranch?
>> It is, yes.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
Did we get Mr. Smith figured out?
I'm going to try again. I'm going to ask
him to unmute. He is unmuted right now.
Mr. Smith, go ahead and talk to us.
Sir?
We can't hear you, sir. We can barely
hear you.
Can you speak a little closer to that
microphone, maybe?
It's getting a little better, sir.
Can you hear me now? We can. Beautiful.
Uh okay. Okay. Um good evening, Mayor
Collins and members of the City Council.
For the record, my name is Charles
Miller, and I'm speaking to demand you
vote no on the Cox Ranch annexation and
its associated zoning changes.
I have listened carefully to the staff
report tonight and the admissions
made on this
this record should alert every citizen
of Laramie County. First, this
annexation fails the basic requirements
of Wyoming law. Under Wyoming statute
15-1-402,
you're required to determine that this
annexation protects the health, safety,
and welfare of the persons residing in
the area. Yet, just minutes ago when Dr.
Aldridge asked how many residents
actually live on this property, city
planner Connor White stated on the
record, "To my knowledge, none. The land
is completely vacant." You cannot check
a statutory box claiming you're
>> Mr. Miller, just read it. It says for
the people in the area being annexed.
So,
the future people are going to live and
work in the area being annexed. Is it
for the health, safety, and welfare of
them?
Uh okay. I'm going to So, it doesn't
mean [clears throat] statute 15-1-402
under those circumstances because you're
right, there's nobody living there, but
there will be somebody living or working
there in the future, and it's our job to
make sure that it's for the health and
safety of the people that are going to
live in that area or work in the area
being annexed.
Gotcha. I'm I'm going to go ahead and
proceed here. Um you cannot check
[clears throat]
a statutory box claiming you are
protecting residents who do not exist.
Um passing this based on a if passing
this based on a fiction is an arbitrary
capricious act. Second, you are handing
developers a blank check and stripping
the public of its voice. When Councilman
Wolf asked what the public's opportunity
would be to weigh in on a future data
center or industrial facility once this
is zoned business park, Mr. White openly
admitted there would be no notice. There
is no public process. It's basically the
city reviews it. If you approve
this annexation tonight, you are
permanently locking the public out of
the process. You are telling the
residents of Laramie County that massive
noisy data centers and industrial
utilities can be built directly adjacent
to their rural homes, and they will
never get a public hearing. Third, the
impacts are real.
>> what are we doing right now, sir?
Mr. Miller, what are we doing right now?
Um I'm I'm just going to go ahead and
continue.
>> are we having a public hearing right
now? We are. We're having one.
>> So, you can't say we're not having a
public hearing. We're doing it right
now, and people are here talking to us.
So, sir, that's factually incorrect.
Um I'm I'm going to go ahead and
continue. I just have a little bit uh
more here. Uh third, the impacts are
real. Mayor Collins, you admitted
yourself tonight that the city learned a
hard lesson from the noise pollution of
a previous Bitcoin mining operation.
Why are we opening the door to repeat
that exact same mistake on a 1,200 acre
scale next
to Happy Jack Road? This annexation does
not fit the neighborhood. It fails the
statutory requirements of protecting
existing residents, and it permanently
silences the public from future
development oversight. Do not trade our
quality of life for a 1,200 acre blind
experiment. I demand you vote no on this
annexation and the associated zoning
changes. Thank you.
Anybody else? Sir, did you want to say
something more?
Just one more thing that I would like to
point out uh uh Paul Kramples again. Um
a short drive west on Happy Jack, if you
would do that tomorrow, you'll find that
this piece of property sits on a hill.
So, everybody that looks out west
including my property
uh
uh is going to see whatever you put up
on that hill. Uh there is no escaping
that. It's not uh
uh
um
basically it ruins the ruins the view.
Somebody else had discussed that, the
wildlife uh and the quality of life
that's out there. Um
uh the mausoleum sits on a hill, and
that and that's
uh that's an issue that you need to deal
with. So, I just wanted to point out
that that is the topography of that, not
just the the the plot, but it's just the
topography uh that that is going to sit
up there where everybody can uh have to
deal with it. Thank you. Thank you.
Jennifer, is there anybody else online?
Uh March, you should be able to unmute
yourself.
Hi.
Um
I am a resident Can you identify
yourself for us, please?
My name is Mandy Schaddack, and I live
at 7505 Barrington Road in Rolling
Hills. Thank you.
I grew up in the neighborhood. Been
there for a long time and back and forth
off and on, and I'm back again.
And I would like to say that so many
people
brought up great points tonight about
the pocket, the environment, and all of
that.
Most of us are on well water, and we
haven't talked about that or the
implication
of building something on top of the hill
when we live below it.
Cheyenne wants to take on more than it
can handle, it seems in my opinion.
And
by annexing this area and wanting to
further the infrastructure out here,
however that looks,
is going to impact not just the animals,
not just the people, but ultimately the
water.
And as we're looking across the country
right now, and even just down south in
Colorado, water is an issue.
And
what are we doing?
It's cute that we painted uh our water
tower with really expensive paint.
It appears to me that Cheyenne is more
about the appearances and the facade
than it is about the people.
And the people of this area live here
for a reason, and they've spoken.
And I have a feeling that you've already
made up your minds behind closed doors.
I appreciate you giving us the
opportunity to speak, and I hope it
works in our favor. Thank you. Thanks,
Mandy.
Jennifer, anybody else?
Anybody else in the room?
Well, hearing none, the purpose of the
public hearing has been met. And let's
talk about the next steps, okay? So,
this public hearing was to give us an
opportunity to hear what's going on. The
next step will be next Monday at noon in
this room. The Public Services Committee
will meet and it'll be the first step in
the zone change, the sign zoning, and
the annexation.
Uh the following Monday, 2 weeks from
today, would be the second time that we
will get together as a governing body to
to look at those things. And that'll be
the first official vote of the City
Council. And then, if it were to pass on
that Monday,
uh then it would go back to the Public
Services Committee where again the
zoning, the annexation, the zone change,
and the land use change would all be up
for uh discussion at that Public Service
meeting. And then it would come back to
us again the following Monday for the
final vote of the governing body if they
were to pass throughout this whole
process.
So, I appreciate everybody being here
tonight. And if you wanted to be part of
that process, that's how that would
work.
Thank you.
Next item, please, Madam Clerk.
Number eight, ordinance third reading
amending the official zoning map of the
City of Cheyenne, changing the zoning
classification for land located north of
West College Drive and east of South
Parsley Boulevard from PUD Harmony
Valley Planned Unit Development to NR3
Neighborhood Residential High Density.
I maybe we'll just take a minute here
and let people who are ready to leave do
so and then we'll catch back up. So,
give me just a second.
>> [snorts]
>> All right, we have before us a 6.5
acre zone change from PUD to mixed-use
commercial. That is, I believe, the the
plan is for the building of some
apartment units and we'll open it up to
the public to see if they have any
comments on the zone change before us.
Hearing none, Dr. Emmons.
Oh.
Sir.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but it's
neighborhood high-density residential.
Mr. Love, identify yourself.
>> Uh sorry, my name is Steven Love. I live
in Ward 1.
>> you and me, before we go any further.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh is it ne- not neighborhood?
Uh NR3? Yep, it's neighborhood NR3
neighborhood high-density residential.
>> I'm sorry, you said uh I I must
>> I said I said NR2, didn't I? Or NR3?
Yeah. Okay. So, good evening, Mr. Mayor.
Through you to the members of the
Council. My name is Steven Love.
Um first and foremost, I'm always in
favor of landowners and the right to do
what they please with their property. I
think this is an idea that characterizes
anyone who has a true Wyoming first
mindset.
I support Wyoming business owners and
think we should break down many of the
barriers to entry that so many,
especially small business owners, face.
I would like to address some issues that
may come not with these zone changes,
but as a symptom of a larger oversight.
This is an area of ever-increasing
economic growth. With the addition of an
$800 million data center not 1 mile away
in Cheyenne's newest high school having
been completed just 17 years ago,
there's clearly both public and private
interest in the value of this area.
As the City of Cheyenne continues to
permit development in this area, I hope
you will all remember the importance of
parks in our community. Parks are one of
the smartest investments we can make and
the numbers prove it. A study in
Massachusetts calculated every dollar
put into green space returns $4 in
natural goods and services. Children
with access to parks show lower obesity
rates. And in Chicago, areas surrounded
by green space saw a 52% fewer crimes.
Per UDC Article 5.3.9,
the overall density of NR3 zone or NR
Yeah, sorry, the NRZ3
Oh my goodness, should be more than 15
dwelling units per acre.
With all three of these zoning plans
that are coming up in the next um
couple item points, um
a total of 46 acres and a potential for
at least 692 dwellings exists. That will
leave the current our current municipal
options for walkable outdoor recreation
in the South High neighborhood stressed
in a best-case scenario.
So, at this time I ask the city to
investigate the possibility of a
much-needed park to serve serve our
community and maintaining the current
ones in the area.
The biggest necessity in our community
south of the interstate is something
like Cahill or North Park, a large open
space that can be used by all and bring
us together as a community. The schools
are currently our only option. However,
this is not viable for parents of
toddlers as these are generally
restricted to the public in many ways
during school hours.
Aside from the schools, the only real
option in South Cheyenne is South the
South Cheyenne Community Park. However,
this is not an option for many people
who live south of the interstate for
many reasons including the danger of
sending kids several miles to the park,
even with older children.
Not to mention its proximity to the
unhoused shelter.
From an economic standpoint, the
property values in our community have
the potential
of decreasing due to Project Cosmo. And
a large green space could help remedy
some of that burden placed on homeowners
as well by slightly increasing home
values. In conclusion, I'm glad to see
the Council supporting business in our
community. I hope to see even a greater
degree of support to our families,
especially in underrepresented
neighborhoods. Thank you.
Mr. Love, I love that comment and you
know, it's our goal to have a a
neighborhood park within 10-minute
walking distance of everybody that lives
in Cheyenne. I think we're about 85% of
the way there now. And um
since I've been on the City Council, I'm
trying to think of the number. It's like
seven, eight, or nine, something like
that parks we built. And we need to
continue to do that. So, thank you for
your comments. Yes, sir. Thank you.
Anybody else?
Hearing none,
Dr. Emmons. Mr. Mayor, the
recommendation of the Public Service
Committee is to approve on third and
final reading and I so move. Second.
Seconded by Mr. White.
Comments from members of the governing
body? Yes, sir. Dr. Aldrich. Mayor
Collins, through you. Um
I did want to just note that uh talking
about uh green space and um parks was
one of the things that did come up at
the Public Service Committee. And I know
that the developer did have some
um considerations of that when they
presented that to the Public Service
Committee. So, I would encourage um the
public maybe to go back and watch that
recording.
Anyone else?
Hearing none, Madam Clerk, would you
take the vote?
Mr. White.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yes. Mr. Wolf. Yes. Dr. Aldrich. Yes.
Mayor Collins. Yes. Dr. Emmons. Yes. Mr.
Esquibel. Aye.
Mr. Leybourn. Yeah.
Aye. Mr. Moody. Aye. Dr. Rinne.
Yes. Mr. Segrave. Yes.
The ordinance is approved on third and
final reading.
Number nine, ordinance third reading
amending the official zoning map of the
City of Cheyenne, changing the zoning
classification for land located south of
West Allison Road, west of Walter Schied
Boulevard, and north of Grand Harmony
Boulevard from PUD Harmony Valley
Planned Unit Development to NR3
Neighborhood Residential High Density.
All right, before us now we have a 25.17
acre
zone change to go from PUD to NR3. This
would allow for some smaller lots and
smaller homes that have more
affordability. And we'll go out to the
audience to see if anybody has a comment
on this zone change.
Hearing none, Dr. Emmons. Mr. Mayor, the
recommendation of the Public Service
Committee is to approve on third and
final reading and I so move.
Second. Seconded by Mr. Segrave.
Comments from members of the governing
body on the zone change?
Hearing none, Madam Clerk.
Mr. Segrave.
Yes. Mr. White.
>> Yes. Mr. Wolf. Yes. Dr. Aldrich. Yes.
Mayor Collins.
>> Yes. Dr. Emmons. Yes. Mr. Esquibel. Aye.
Mr. Leybourn. Yes. Mr. Moody. Aye. Dr.
Rinne.
Yes.
The ordinance is approved on third and
final reading, also.
Number 10, ordinance third reading
amending the official zoning map of the
City of Cheyenne, changing the zoning
classification for land located north of
Allison Road and west of Walter Schied
Boulevard from AG Agriculture to NR3
Neighborhood Residential High Density.
All right, this is a 14.47
acre um
zone change to go from PUD to NR3 for a
future mixed-use commercial development.
We'll go back out to the audience for
comments.
Hearing none, Dr. Emmons. Mr. Mayor, the
recommendation of the Public Service
Committee is to approve on third and
final reading and I so move. Second.
Seconded by Mr. White.
Comments from members of the governing
body on the zone change?
Hearing none,
Madam Clerk.
Dr. Rinne.
Dr. Rinne, are you there?
Yes, sorry. I had trouble unmuting. Yes.
Mr. Segrave. Yes. Mr. White.
>> Yes. Mr. Wolf. Yes.
Dr. Aldrich. Yes. Mayor Collins. Dr.
Emmons. Yes. Mr. Esquibel. Aye. Mr.
Leybourn. Yes. Mr. Moody. Aye.
The ordinance is approved on third and
final reading.
Number 11, ordinance third reading
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne changing the zoning
classification for land located
northwest of the intersection of East
29th Street and Central Avenue from MR
medium-density residential to NR2
neighborhood residential medium density.
All right, we have
a half an acre that is
currently zoned MR
to
change to MR2 or NR2, excuse me. It's an
existing row of townhomes under one
ownership and they want to split it into
individual lots so they can be sold off.
And so we'll go out to the audience to
see if they have any questions. Anybody?
All right, Dr. Emmons. Mr. Mayor, the
recommendation of the Public Service
Committee is to approve on third and
final reading and I so move.
Second. Seconded by Mr. Segrave.
Any comments from members of the
governing body on this zone change?
Hearing none.
Madam Clerk. Mr. Moody. Aye.
Dr. Rennie.
Yes. Mr. Segrave. Yes. Mr. White. Yes.
Mr. Wolfe. Yes. Dr. Aldrich. Yes. Mayor
Collins.
>> Yes. Dr. Emmons. Yes. Mr. Esquibel. Aye.
Mr. Laybourn. Aye.
The ordinance is approved on third and
final reading.
Number 12, ordinance third reading
vacating Frank Court and a small segment
of a previously vacated alley north of
Rock Springs Street, City of Cheyenne,
Laramie County, Wyoming located east of
North College Drive and north of Rock
Springs Street. All right, this is an
ordinance to
vacate or remove an underutilized street
that just serves one property and they
have a different entrance.
We'll go out to the audience and see if
anybody wants to speak to the vacation
of this street.
All right, Dr. Emmons.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
Public Service Committee is to approve
on second reading and I so move. Second.
Seconded by Mr. White.
Comments from members of the governing
body on the vacation?
Hearing none.
Madam Clerk.
Mr. Laybourn.
Aye. Mr. Moody. Aye. Dr. Rennie.
Yes. Mr. Segrave. Yes. Mr. White. Yes.
Mr. Wolfe. Yes. Dr. Aldrich. Yes. Mayor
Collins.
Dr. Emmons. Yes. Mr. Esquibel. Aye.
This ordinance is also approved on third
and final reading.
Number 13, ordinance second reading
amending section 13.20.050
general prohibitions and section
13.20.070
local limits of chapter 13.20 wastewater
treatment and disposal of the code of
the City of Cheyenne, Wyoming to revise
local discharge limits and related
provisions in compliance with NPDES and
WPDES permit requirements. I tried to
read this and it was a little hard on
me. I had to look up things every time
but every court paragraph but it's an
update of our wastewater regulations and
we'll go out to the audience see if
anybody has any questions.
Mayor Collins, members of the council.
Matt Buelow, Cheyenne, Wyoming, Board of
Public Utilities, Water Reclamation
Division Manager. So what this is, this
is way I can put it, is everything that
comes into the two wastewater treatment
plants is a pie. Everyone that comes in
has a piece of that pie and this is just
limiting everybody that could send us
possibly something bad into the
wastewater treatment facilities to one
protect the citizens of Cheyenne,
protect the workers of the wastewater
treatment plants and protect the users
of downstream of wastewater. I'd be
happy to answer any questions. Thanks
for being here, Matt.
Anybody else in the audience want to
speak to this ordinance on second
reading?
All right, hearing none. Dr. Emmons. Mr.
Mayor, the recommendation of the Public
Service Committee is to approve on
second reading and I so move. Second.
Seconded by Mr. Segrave.
Any comments by members of the governing
body?
Hearing none, all those in favor please
signify by saying aye. Aye.
Those opposed? This ordinance is
approved on second reading.
Number 14, ordinance second reading
amending section 2.76.040
designation of downtown development
district of chapter 2.76 downtown
development authority of title two
administration and personnel of the
municipal code of the City of Cheyenne,
Wyoming to expand the downtown
development district.
Well, we have some good news. We have a
business, I guess, Snyder Foods that's
asked to be incorporated into our
downtown development authority um
district. Uh anybody in the audience
want to speak to that? Sophia.
Mayor, through you. Um my name is Sophia
Mays, Executive Director of the Downtown
Development Authority. Um this is an
ordinance to amend the city code to
include the property at 2100 Snyder
Avenue, also known as Snyder Food.
Uh this ordinance follows the resolution
that council passed on February 23rd,
2026 to support this expansion. The
signed resolution is attached in the
council packet provided to you all.
2100 Snyder is contiguous to the
downtown district boundary along Snyder
Avenue.
The property owners began the petition
process for inclusion into the district
in November 2025 with the DDA board
approving the petition and recommending
inclusion to the governing body at its
regular meeting on January 15th, 2026.
The inclusion of this property would
include all adjacent rights-of-way
including but not limited to Snyder
Avenue on the east, West 21st Street on
the south, and the adjacent alley on the
north side.
The property has long been home to
Snyder Food, a locally owned and
operating store serving the West Edge
area.
Inclusion of this property advances the
DDA statutory purpose to prevent blight
and support property values within the
downtown district. Inclusion would
include would
excuse me, inclusion would allow DDA
programs to be utilized allowing
infrastructure and property improvements
to the area improving functionality and
visual appeal while supporting private
investment in the downtown built
environment. DDA staff recommends
approval of the ordinance before you and
I stand for questions.
Thank you, ma'am.
Any questions for staff?
Anybody else in the audience want to
speak on the
expansion of our downtown development
district?
I hear none. Dr. Emmons.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
Public Service Committee is to approve
on second reading and I so move. Second.
Seconded by Mr. White. Comments from
members of the governing body on this
ordinance.
Mr. Mayor. Mr. White. Just through you,
I just wanted to remind
my colleagues it's been a while
but the owner of this business was very
enthusiastic back in January
when we heard from him on the resolution
and really wanted to be
included in the DDA district and
just talked about some exciting things
that he may have going on for this
particular piece of property. So I'm
very supportive of this.
You know, I think um
the thing that's amazing is people who
are in the DDA district actually pay 20
mils more in property taxes than anybody
else in the city does and those dollars
go back to improving the DDA. So asking
somebody to tax themselves so they can
improve downtown is something.
And he was fully aware of that and and
still very supportive and asking us to
do this for him. So
That's wonderful. Thank you for the
story. Anybody else in the governing
body comments?
Hearing none, all those in favor please
signify by saying aye. Aye. Those
opposed? This ordinance is approved on
second reading.
Number 15, ordinance second reading
appropriating money for the Reed Avenue
Corridor project. All right, this is an
ordinance that would earmark $5 million
to invest in our Reed Avenue project if
and when the Burlington Northern
Railroad tells us we can do that. And so
we'll go out to the audience and I'm
going to guess
Hello, Mayor and Council. For the
record, Sophia Mays from the Executive
Director of the Downtown Development
Authority as well.
Again, the Downtown Development
Authority at their March 19th regular
board meeting signed a letter of
support. I apologize I I
failed to send it to the entire council
but the Finance Committee did receive a
copy of that signed letter for this
ordinance.
This project, the Reed Rail project, is
a catalyst project in the downtown plan
and development. We
are supportive as an organization of
this project and the $5 million being
committed to this
depending on the
agreements with the BNSF.
We're very confident in the talks that
we've heard from the Director Cobb as
well as
with BNSF and
we we also think that the the
improvements to this area will transform
the West Edge
as outlined in our 20
18, I believe was when it was adopted,
West Edge area-wide plan.
Thank you.
Thanks, Sophia.
Your little guy's doing great.
Goodness. Um Brendan Westby from 714
West 20th, Westby Edge Brewing. Um Mayor
and City Council members, I just wanted
to say once again I appreciate all the
work that's gone into this project and
just how much it means to us
that we invested our money into this
property specifically for hopefully this
project going through and I know that
the
um railroad can be the railroad and it's
causing some problems but I just love
seeing this process go through and I'm
happy to be a part of it. Thank you. You
know, I think the railroad is going to
be at railroad and they've been a
they've been a good partner. They're
just slow. They are very deliberate in
their processes, but we've been making
very steady progress and we just want to
say thank you to you and your family for
your investment. You were the first you
and
Dave Tubner were the first two to really
jump on the vision that we have here.
Thank you for that.
Anybody else?
I see your hand.
Who do you have, Jennifer?
Uh Mr. Smith, you should be able to
unmute yourself or I'm sorry, Mr.
Miller.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Okay. Good evening, Mayor Collins and
members of the City Council. For the
record, my name
is Charles Miller. I'm speaking on item
15 regarding the Reed Avenue Corridor
funding. I'm looking at the text of this
ordinance and it is a textbook example
of misplaced prior
priorities.
The ordinance admits that the Reed
Avenue project was cut from the
six-penny tax ballot due to funding
limitations. So, instead of letting the
voters decide, you are bypassing the
ballot and pulling 5 million directly
out of the city's general fund reserves.
On top of that, later tonight, you are
spending another $650,000
to buy private properties on Reed
Avenue.
Um you're pulling over $5.6 million out
of our reserves for a corridor project.
Yet, the Board of Public Utilities
admits that we have 28
thousand
service lines made of 25 homes exceeded
the EPA's absolute max
maximum action level for lead.
I'm sorry, excuse me.
If you have $5 million
sitting in the general fund reserves to
build a corridor, you have $5 million to
replace toxic lead pipes. You cannot
claim poverty on public health while
writing yourselves a $5.6 million check
from the reserves
for discretionary real estate and
corridors. You spent federal COVID
relief money on flock surveillance
cameras instead of safe water and now
you are draining the reserves for Reed
Avenue while leaving thousands of
families playing Russian roulette with
their tap water. I demand you vote no on
appropriating these reserves for Reed
Avenue until a plan is fully funded to
address the lead crisis in our in the
city. Fix the lead first. Thank you.
Anybody else?
All right, we'll go to Mr. Escobel for a
motion, please. Mr. Mayor, the
recommendation of the Finance Committee
second reading and I so move. Seconded
by Mr. Laybourn.
All right, comments from members of the
governing body on the ordinance.
Mr. Escobel, did Nope.
Mr. White, go ahead.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Uh just to address
one of the comments that was just
previously made.
Um
It was not cut This project was not cut
from the six-penny ballot due to
insufficient funds as was suggested. It
was cut from the six-penny ballot
because it we did not have enough money
allocated to city to include all of the
city projects that we wanted to on the
ballot. So, I think
an important distinction needs to be
made there.
Um secondly,
this project is a long time coming.
Um we've experienced numerous delays um
due to the fact that as the mayor
alluded to, the railroad works on its
own specific timeline.
However, we've never been closer
to
seeing this project succeed than we are
now. And the most recent conversations,
direct conversations I might add, that
we have had with the railroad have been
very
positive and constructive. Essentially,
um they've agreed to it. We don't have
anything in writing yet. And this
ordinance specifically references that
that no funds will be allocated until
there is a um final written agreement.
However,
they essentially have given the green
light um
with the condition of some closures. And
while the closures are certain to be
inconvenient for some folks, those
closures are of the utmost importance to
the railroad um for safety.
Uh
additionally,
the most recent uh conversations have
seemingly come up to to
uh with a solution
for Westside pedestrian access as well.
While not perfect, um
it will be there. And so, um
I'm pleased to support this. I
appreciate the investment that's been
made,
uh the millions of dollars in capital
investment that we've seen in this area.
The owners of the businesses have long
awaited
some movement on this project and we
seemingly have it. So, the fact that we
are putting our skin in the game as
those folks have already put their skin
in the game and the fact that the
final sentence of section two
specifically states that no funds shall
be expended from this commitment until a
final agreement with the Burlington
Northern Santa Fe Railroad has been
reached makes me happy to be a
co-sponsor and happy to vote yes on
this.
Dr. Alders. Mayor Collins, for you.
Um I would just like to point out that
the voters actually did vote to support
this project in 2017 is when this
project first started. So, the idea that
this has never gone before the voters is
um not accurate. I also um would concur
with my colleague from Ward 1 that um I
believe it's really important that when
the voters um put a task before us or a
project before us, that we make the
commitment to complete that task and to
follow through um with that. Um I
did um I do believe that it is for um
the Burlington Northern is concerned
about safety for their employees and for
um the trains coming through, but I
really believe that this is um an
important factor for safety for our
community members. Um and I'm not saying
that it is any more or less important
than um lead pipes, but I do believe
that um
public safety is public safety and
having safe crossing and safe access
um on the west edge of town is just as
important um as
taking care of our lead pipes.
And I will be a yes vote on this tonight
because I believe that um
this resolution actually um
dedicates this funding only if uh we get
the final approval from the Burlington
Northern um railroad and uh there's been
a lot of progress, although it's been
slow, I think um being made just because
as the mayor mentioned, that's how
the railroad functions
um and they have their process.
Um but I believe that if we were to um
not go forward with this, that any money
that we have invested as a community and
as a city
would be a loss and we would be back um
at square one and all of the money we've
invested in this so far, we would be
basically starting over again. I'm not
willing to take taxpayer money um and
throw away the work that's been done
just to start over again on a new
process down the road. So, for that
reason, I'll be a yes vote tonight.
Anybody else?
Yes, ma'am.
Dr. Munis. Uh thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um
I'm going to be a a yes vote on this for
two reasons and and to be really honest,
I've struggled with this, but I I come
to this side and there's two reasons
that that I want to say. One is this
weekend this weekend, many of us had the
opportunity to listen to an amazing
speaker whose name I can't remember.
Ches- Chester McKee? Justin McKee.
Justin McKee, who is very important in
the rodeo world.
Much more important than I know about.
But, he was an amazing speaker who spoke
highly
about Cheyenne being a community that's
willing to take some risks
and to stand out
and to be progressive and to move
forward and
to embrace the opportunities we have.
And I think this is a huge opportunity
that we have. And is it going to cost
some money? Yes, it is. Is it an
investment? Yes, it is. And it's going
to turn around um
on the backside as far as resources
coming into the city. So,
after I listened to Mr. McKee, I
thought, you know, we are that community
and we do need to embrace that. We need
to remember it and we need to be okay
with that. If and like I say, we need to
embrace it. The second thing, the reason
that um
I'm going to be a yes and I want to
respond to the the caller.
In my day job, I do public health
every day, 24 hours a day and I would
raise 14 kinds of hell
if I thought we had lead pipes that were
not being taken care of so we could do
this. So, I hope the caller and anyone
else in the community understands that
our water is safe. We monitor it. BOPU
does an amazing job with it. I look at
lead levels on kids and adults every
day. It's not there. So, I just want to
put that out to the caller and anybody
else that's listening. We do have good,
safe water.
And this is an investment in the
community that we need to make. So,
thank you. Jennifer, is that Dr. Rennie?
Please.
Dr. Rennie.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Um
I am going to be a no vote on this, but
I want to
back up a little bit and
just explain why.
Um first of all, I think I'm the only
council member here that was
or still on the council that was present
when this when the Reed Avenue corridor
and the West Edge improvements
were first proposed by Jean McDonald and
Matt Ashby.
And then council my colleague Councilman
White and I were the only ones I think
on council
um present now that
were advocates for getting this on on
the 6-penny ballot in 2017. So, I've
been an an advocate and a proponent and
supporter of of the Reed Avenue project
um
going back for almost a decade.
Um
but I don't like the timing on this. I
think that
the one
um
you know, commits 5 million. It's an
ordinance, not a resolution, so it
commits 5 million dollars by law
and does not give us any flexibility if
we happen to have an emergency later on.
One of our other colleagues has
advocated that he wants to add an
additional 4 million dollars for
stormwater drainage to the budget
this upcoming year and we and we haven't
even seen your budget yet to see where
it goes, Mayor. So,
um so, from a fiscal standpoint, I don't
don't think it's prudent yet to be doing
this. And in addition, you've already
given us your assurances or pledged that
if the the NSF came through, you would
look for funding to to further the um
project. And I do want to add, I want to
echo what my colleague from ward ward
three said a little while ago. This was
approved by the voters in 2017.
And at the time um
when we proposed it, we knew that the
the money's allotted wouldn't be enough
to do the entire corridor.
But we also knew that it would get the
planning done and get us a good start on
it. And we also knew that at some point
we would have to come back for more
more funds. So,
um
so, as I said, Mr. Mayor, I I have
always supported the project, but I do
not support the timing of the ordinance.
Thank you.
Mr. Laybourn, did you want to speak? I
think Mr. Wolf's got something to say.
Mr. Wolf. Uh Mr. Mayor, thank you. Um
I I'm going to vote strongly in favor of
this. Uh
I've been on the council about 4 months.
It's really the first project that um I
um I dove into uh
um the very first meetings at um at
Westby property to talk with the
landowners um there and the investors uh
and uh
I think um
I think this is ready to go. I applaud
our city engineer uh Mr. Cobb has done a
um incredible job
with this and thinking it through and
working through the details. Um
very appreciative of Mr. Cobb and and
the mayor for
the works that they've um continued to
do with the railroad. Um and um
and I think we we are ready to move this
forward. Uh and we owe it to the voters
to um to proceed with it. We owe it to
the people who've made uh investments
there already. And we owe it to the
community. And the community in that
part of uh Cheyenne is really really
changing for the better.
Uh and um I think we would miss an
incredible opportunity if we don't
follow through with this. And so, I'll
be a yes. Thank you very much.
Mr. Trebel.
Mr. Mayor, through you
uh in 1908, if that city council had the
vision
of what this would be like, uh
we probably already have this project
done. But not only that, it's the
private investments that's been made by
a number of uh families in this
community.
And they have a vision as well.
And I think this is
our way of showing our commitment as
well
to not just the voters, uh but the
private investments that have been made.
And for you those of you out in the
audience who wonder why 1908 is
important, in 1908, the Cheyenne City
Council gave the right of way of Reed
Avenue to the Colorado River or Colorado
River, I'm thinking water, the Colorado
Railroad um because it back in those
days, if you think about it, we didn't
have semis and we didn't have
interstates.
Goods came by rail. And so, they built
warehouses along there and the trains
brought the goods that that we needed
here in Cheyenne. Things have changed
and those warehouses are now under
underutilized. And
um and so, that's why this project was
was brought to to pass. Mr. Laybourn.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I speak in favor
of this action.
And
actually, uh certainly I think we need
to reflect on going even further back
than 2017, which is when the voters
approved the initial funding for this.
Let's go all the way back to when this
building was built.
And and along the way, let's take a look
at some of the other things that have
happened uh in this neighborhood uh in
the more recent past. The library,
the Board of Public Utilities building,
the uh
recently, [clears throat]
uh
medical building there at uh
uh nearby.
So, the Children's Museum,
uh HealthWorks is
the word I was searching for.
So, it's it's a and of course, above
all,
the uh
apartment complex going in uh
practically catty-corner from us.
So, there's a whole movement
to the disadvantaged neighborhood.
And certainly uh the ability to
revitalize those buildings
as the Westbys have done is uh
really a worthwhile uh goal because
you're
there's a rebirth factor there. This is
This isn't an unusual project, but I
would point out that it is the Greenway
connection
to our downtown.
And it's going to be a non-motorized
improvement to that infrastructure
just like a road.
So, I think that when we look at this,
we need to consider what has happened
over time and what is going to happen
over time as this continues. There is
a and has been a uh movement among
property owners uh
to take advantage of this.
I think there are people that are
waiting for it, that own property, that
have bought property.
And it's going to be uh over time
something that's very worthwhile.
I do want to respond to one of the
concerns that was raised in committee.
And that was the question of
gentrification.
Well, gentrification might happen
somewhere. I don't know
where that is or how that happens, but
that's a process where people that live
in the neighborhood are priced out.
Uh this is not the case
here in Cheyenne. This is not the case
in West Cheyenne. In fact, just the
opposite is happening.
We're seeing properties that uh
are are being rehabilitated due to cost.
We've seen that we rezoned uh West there
of Snyder so that it was easier for
people to do that.
We're working on the either re Excuse
me. Rehabilitation of some of these
damaged
or their removal. And I point out that
uh there's a number
of vacant
uh parcels and lots in that area
that are adjacent to the streets, have
water, sewer,
power connections that are just waiting
for further investment. And those people
are making those investments. So, it
isn't a question of pricing anybody out.
It's a question of elevating the whole
neighborhood, including the people that
currently live there and the people that
are going to want to live there.
So, it's a it's a real big step for
Cheyenne to take on something like this.
It's been very difficult and
frustrating, but
as the chairman of the Reed Avenue
Steering Committee,
I applaud uh Mr.
Cobb's determination here through time
that we see this through. And I think
the council ought to follow up on that
tonight. And uh
it will will see what happens here.
Obviously, nothing until the the final
agreement, but
uh more than anything else, I see the
investment that's happening on the west
side here and that's happening along
that corridor as being the ultimate
proof that this is basically a uh
it's a stretch. It's a different idea,
but it's one that's going to bear fruit.
So,
uh thank you.
Anybody else in the governing body?
All right, we have an ordinance on
second reading to appropriate 5 million
dollars to the Reed Avenue. All those in
favor, please signify by saying I. I.
Those opposed? No.
Mr. Moody and Dr. Rennie are no's.
The ordinance is approved on second
reading.
Number 16 ordinance first reading
amending the official zoning map of the
city of Cheyenne changing the zoning
classification for land located south of
I-80 east of Southwest Drive from County
LI light industrial AG agricultural and
AR agricultural residential to LI light
industrial.
We'll refer this one to the Public
Services Committee. Number 17 ordinance
first reading pursuant to section 2.2.2
planned development regulating plan or
development master plan and section
5.6.2 PUD planned unit development
district of the unified development code
amending ordinance number 4524 by
modifying certain standards of the
adopted district planned unit
development PUD for Sweet Grass located
southeast of the intersection of College
Drive and Avenue C.
We'll refer this one to the Public
Services Committee. Number 18 ordinance
first reading annexing to the city of
Cheyenne, Wyoming land west of Roundtop
Road to adjacent to Happy Jack Road.
We'll send this one to the Public
Services Committee. Number 19 ordinance
first reading amending the official
zoning map of the city of Cheyenne
establishing the zoning classification
of AG agricultural and P public for land
annexed to the city of Cheyenne located
west of Roundtop Road and adjacent to
Happy Jack Road. This one will also go
to Public Services Committee. Number 20
ordinance first reading amending the
official zoning map of the city of
Cheyenne changing the zoning
classification for land located west of
Roundtop Road and adjacent to Happy Jack
Road from AG agricultural to BP business
park. Dr. Emmons, your committee's going
to be busy. This one will also go to the
Public Services Committee.
Number 21 resolution authorizing the
mayor and city clerk to sign a final
plat for 2900 Central Avenue townhomes
city of Cheyenne, Laramie County,
Wyoming located northwest of the
intersection of East 29th Street and
Central Avenue. All right, this is
the final plat for the zone that we did
just a couple minutes ago
to take the
one large lot and and split it up into
the existing single townhome lots and we
had to do that first before we can do
the plat. So that's why we took it off
the consent agenda.
We'll go out to the audience if anybody
wanted to speak to this final plat.
Hearing none, Dr. Emmons. Mr. Mayor, the
recommendation of the Public Service
Committee is to adopt and I so move.
Second. Seconded by Mr. Seagrave.
Comments from members of the governing
body on the final plat.
Hearing none, all those in favor, please
signify by saying I. I. Those opposed?
This final plat is adopted.
Number 22 resolution approving and
adopting the city of Cheyenne crosswalk
criteria and guidelines and confirming
the authority of the city engineer to
implement crosswalk treatments. All
right, this is an update to our our
rules regarding crosswalks to give our
engineering department maybe a little
more flexibility in the sighting of
crosswalks. Anybody in the audience want
to speak to that?
You don't have to.
I'm going to hold you to that one.
Welcome back. It's good to see you. Push
the button, introduce yourself, please.
My name is Carol Davinroy. I live on
Spirit Lane in Cheyenne.
>> Carol.
Thank you. Haven't been here for a long
time.
Um I just well, I want to thank
um
Mr. Cobb and Mr. Ammons for their
persistence in getting this going and
done and I know it was a huge project.
But I also wanted to thank um
Tom Mr. Tom Seagrave thanking him for
his support and some of the other
um council members as well, Mr. Laybourn
as example. But um
Mr. [clears throat] Seagrave did at the
Public Services Committee ask Mr. Ammons
if the if Gardenia would qualify for
with these
um criteria that have been developed and
um Mr. Ammons answered in the
affirmative. So I'm I just want to get
that on the record. And he also asked
Mr. Ammons for a time frame. Thank you,
Mr. Seagrave. And the time frame is this
summer.
Probably late summer, but I think he
said late summer. But nevertheless, this
summer. So yay, we may be getting well,
hopefully getting
a crosswalk.
So I want to thank you very much for
your work on it.
But it isn't done till the fat lady
sings, so I'm waiting. She's warmed up
though, Carol.
Thank you. Thank you for being here.
Push that button. There you go. Mr.
Mayor, council members
Bonnie Jo Cruz, I also live on Spirit
Lane.
And I'm going to do exactly the opposite
of what my debate
teacher, who was a very strict nun,
taught me in high school.
>> [sighs]
>> Shame on me and shame on you and the
rest of the people of Cheyenne that it
took the death of a young boy to get
a stoplight by McCormick High School.
My husband and I had three kids that
went to McCormick over 40-some-odd years
ago. Never once did we ever think about
there would ever be a problem of them
crossing the street.
We've progressed, cell phones,
black hoodies, going to school early.
My father always said to me the reason
that windshields are big is so that you
can look out
and not spend so much time looking in
the small rearview mirror.
I want to thank you, Mr. Mayor and
council members,
for addressing this task.
The need of crosswalks in our city, as
you said, Mr. Mayor, we have grown so
much.
Tonight you can all go to bed
and think if what I have done today
saves one life,
saves one person
for a permanent from getting a permanent
disability, you can sleep
without nightmares. Thank you.
Sister Rosita was the one that got after
me, so I remember those days.
Thank you.
Anybody else?
Anybody else in the audience? All right,
Dr. Emmons.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
Public Service Committee is to adopt and
I so move. Second. Seconded by Mr.
Laybourn.
All right, folks, anybody in the
governing body want to speak to this
crosswalk criteria? Mr. Laybourn.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um
I
really appreciate all that went into
this. The uh
Manual of Uniform Traffic
What's the last uh
part of that acronym?
>> devices
devices
uh
obviously is there for a reason. Uh we
want to have uniformity in our
uh traffic control
and yet it really wasn't based on
something that was effective here.
So this is something that I think is uh
very important and very worthwhile not
only for
the long-standing issue uh there on
Gardenia,
but throughout the city as well. There
are This is really something that
is part of
uh
a better understanding of how we achieve
that Vision Zero uh
goal that we've adopted, which is an end
to traffic-related pedestrian deaths.
And so although we've had
too many,
um I think we're headed in the right
direction.
And I do have a question for Mr.
[snorts] Cobb, Mr. Mayor.
Mr. Cobb,
do I
do I understand that the action we're
taking tonight is
the recognition of the existing report,
but that you'll be looking at these
situations
in other places uh with a more
uh
lenient and realistic approach?
Mr. Cobb, [clears throat] I'm not sure
lenient and realistic is the words
you're looking for, but sir. Uh Mayor,
through you to Councilman Laybourn, I
would say, sir, that we are looking at
trying to Yes, the answer is yes, that
we're looking at all crosswalks in a
different way now, but I would say it
aligns better with our population, our
climate, and our use, um not more
lenient.
Does that make sense, sir?
Yes, thank [clears throat] you. And it
is uh something we will be
I I expect that uh other people that
have these issues in their neighborhood
will look on what has been the uh
very determined and long-standing effort
of uh these individuals uh to seek that
sort of uh improvement. So uh thank you
for what you've done and I look forward
to our continuing discussion. Thank you.
Uh thank you, Mr. Mayor. I just wanted
to number one, thank um
City Engineer Cobb and and Mr. Ammons
for all the work that they did on this.
This issue is very important to me
and Mr. Laybourn and Mr. Mooney as well.
We've the three of us have been working
on traffic safety for the last couple of
years. But, I really wanted to thank Ms.
Dana Boy
and Ms. Cruz for spearheading this.
You You Sorry.
Did I get the wrong name? Sorry. I want
to thank Ms. Dana Boy and everyone else
who spearheaded this
because
you were the drivers. If If it hadn't
have been for the two of you, I don't
know that we would have gotten here. And
I know it wasn't quickly to you. It
wasn't quickly for any of us here,
either. But, I don't think we would be
where we're at right now without you
two. And so, while I can appreciate
manuals and warrants,
manuals and warrants to me shouldn't
take the place of common sense.
And I think because of your efforts, and
because of the effort of the consultant
that
we enlisted to study this, I think we're
in a much better place than we were
before you took up this flag and carried
it across the goal line. So, you all
should be really commended.
Please know,
and I know that the process was
frustrating for you.
I've
I've been in Mr. Cobb's office numerous
times about trying to get a crosswalk or
or flashing lights or wherever
for for an area in my ward. So, I do
understand
how um
endless
it may seem. But, uh
you You folks are the reason that we're
where we're at now. And I think we're in
a much better place than when we
started. So, thank you.
Mr. Moody. Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor,
through you. And I do want to echo both
my colleagues that spoke. Like I said,
we are some as passionate about it. And
I agree
one child even just hit by a car
pedestrian is one too many. I've been
saying that harping on that since we had
our city goal last year with traffic
safety.
But, I did want to say with this plan
here,
I do want to see more involved. And I
want to ask Mr. Cobb, is there a chance
we conclude that all crosswalks have
thermal plastic? Not only would it be
from a safety perspective, but also a
fiscal perspective because to me they
last longer and they're more visible
when compared to the paint. Mr. Cobb,
can you talk about your painting plans?
Mayor, through you to Councilman Moody.
Councilman, I I agree with you that in
most cases we do want thermal plastic,
and I think Mr. Amundson reiterated that
same comment to you during committee.
There are occasions where we cannot use
it, and we have good reasons.
For instance, just what we we spoke One
of the questions came up with Mr.
Leybourne about Yellowstone. Um
obviously, we have a major maintenance
project coming where we'll eventually
replace all of it with thermal plastic,
but the timing is not now. So, again, I
prefer to do that not really in the
manual to specify it. We do that on a
project by project basis where it makes
sense, and let us use our engineering
judgment to to make those kind of
decisions, sir. All right.
Thank you. And then I'll just say our
Ridge Road by Classical Academy, if that
can be looked at. I've actually been in
contact with them. That is a major, and
they're just asking can there please be
a crosswalk or even a I know it was a
new name, but I still use the one of
Hawk system there just for the safety of
our children.
Mayor, through you to Councilman Moody,
we we definitely will look at it, sir.
Thank you.
Anybody else?
All right, hearing none. We have a
resolution on
changing our or adding to our crosswalk
criteria. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I. I. Those opposed?
This resolution is adopted.
Next item is number 31C on page five.
Professional services agreement between
the City of Cheyenne and McGee Hearne &
Paiz LLP doing business as MHP Assurance
Services LLP for auditing the annual
financial statements of the City of
Cheyenne, Wyoming and its Board of
Public Utilities.
All right, we have a
a contract here to extend the services
of MHP
to do our annual audit. We'll go out to
the audience. Does anybody want to talk
about our choice of MHP for our auditor?
All right, hearing none. That would be
Mr. Escobar, I believe.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
Finance Committee is to approve in the
amount not to exceed $548,000
and $600 for a period of 3 years, and I
so move. Second. Seconded by Mr. Moody.
Comments from members of the governing
body, Mr. Leybourne. Thank you, Mr.
Mayor. Well, the point I want to make is
that
we're fully accountable for our funds
here.
And not only are we fully accountable
as through the Treasurer's office,
we're fully accountable through the
audit.
So, if anyone has questions about any
sort of funding mechanism or taxes,
where they go, what they do, uh
that's totally and absolutely open for
anyone's inspection. And it is
furthermore
documented in that audit. So,
um sometimes we hear people suggest that
we have a some sort of a slush fund or
some sort of unaccountable system. Not
true. And furthermore,
I can assure anyone that if they want to
know anything about our financial
expenditures,
our Treasurer's office is ready to
answer them in a timely manner. Thank
you.
And I'll just add on to that, too. All
of our
our audits Our audits cover all of our
most of our grants on a regular basis.
So, not only does it cover our general
fund revenues, but all of our grants,
also. So, thank you for that.
Anybody else?
All right, hearing none. All those in
favor of the professional services
agreement, please signify by saying I.
I. Those opposed? That professional
service agreement is approved.
Next item is number 32A on page six.
Contract modification number one to
contract number 8169 between the City of
Cheyenne and JTL Group Inc. doing
business as Knife River for the 2025
City Overlay Number One project.
All right, this is just an extension of
our
our current city overlay project, and
there's Cheshire Drive. We'll go out to
the audience. Does anybody have any
questions on this contract modification
number one?
Hearing none, Mr. Escobar.
Mr. Mayor, this item was reviewed under
other items for the agenda at the April
7th, 2026 Finance Committee meeting.
Therefore, provisions of title two of
the city code have been met.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
Finance Committee is to approve in an
amount not to exceed $217,150.20,
and I so move. Second. Seconded by Mr.
White.
Any comments from members of the
governing body?
Yes. Yes, sir. Dr. Aldrich. Mayor
Collins, I am wondering if um we might
be able to have an explanation of um
maybe what it sounds It looks like from
the description of changes that this was
um
when it was [clears throat] originally
the bid was let that there was not
communication between a couple of our
departments about what was going on. And
so, then that resulted in this
modification of almost a quarter of a
million dollars.
>> Let's get you an answer.
Doug Welcome.
Good evening, Mr. Mayor. Doug Welcome,
City Construction Manager.
Uh through you, Mr. Mayor, Dr. Aldrich,
that's correct. We We did not have the
timing down as to when the Street and
Alley Division wanted to do their
portion of Conn Court, and it and it did
not overlap the way that it should have.
So, that's the reason for the gap. We We
want to fill that and not leave
um
gaps as we do these maintenance
projects. And And so, now we've um
in the past year, we have a better
system set up where we meet with the
with those departments in addition to
the Board of Public Utilities, and we're
trying to coordinate all of our projects
so that we don't have these gaps again
in the future.
Follow up, Dr. Aldrich.
Mayor Collins, to you. I just um
I I just have seen a couple of these
change modifications coming through, not
just for street and um repairs and
maintenance, but um
we just had one recently on some work or
a plan that was being done for City
Hall. And I just I really am concerned
that we continue to see modifications,
and these are ranging in the 200 to
quarter of a million dollar range, and
that
I want to make sure that we're being
fair to all of the people who are
bidding in the process.
So, if we can I appreciate the effort to
communicate better so that we might be
able to when we let these bids to
actually be letting the bid for the work
we actually want done in its entirety,
not in where we're going to have to
piecemeal and come back for these
modifications.
Thank you. Anybody else on the governing
body?
Hearing none, all those in favor, please
signify by saying I. I. Those opposed?
This contract modification is approved.
Next item is number 35A on page eight.
Voucher report.
All right, is there anybody in the
audience or in the governing body that
would like to speak to vouchers?
Hearing none, next item.
35B, designation of the official voting
delegate and alternate delegate for the
City of Cheyenne at the June 4th, 2026
Wyoming Association of Municipalities
Summer Convention Business Meeting to be
held in Laramie, Wyoming.
Annually, we have a
Wyoming Association of Municipalities
um conference, and we have to designate
uh a person to be our voting delegate.
Um that's what this is designed for. Is
there anybody in the audience who would
like to speak to
that topic?
Okay, hearing none, Mr. Escobedo.
Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
Finance Committee is to designate Dr.
Mark Greaney as the official voting
delegate and Mayor Patrick Collins as
the alternate delegate, and I so move.
Second. Seconded by Mr. White. Comments
on the uh motion of Dr. Greaney as our
delegate. I'll just say real quick.
Yes. Yeah. Thank you, Mr. Mayor, through
you. Um I was an abstention not an iron
native. Just want to make sure no
conflicts of interest, and there are no
conflicts of interest, so I'll be an I
vote. Thank you.
Any other comments?
Hearing none, all those in favor of the
designation of Dr. Greaney as a
delegate, myself as the alternate,
please signify by saying I. I. Those
opposed?
This uh designation is adopted.
Number 36, other business. All right, is
there anybody in the audience here today
that would like to speak to us under
other business?
You guys sat through a long meeting to
talk to us, so
welcome.
Do you have Do me a favor, push that
button. Yep. Good evening.
>> Bring Bring that microphone up so it
points at you.
And introduce yourself.
Uh my name is Noel Lechere. I'm a
representative for the Southwest
Regional Council of Carpenters.
Um
I'd like to speak tonight um on tax
fraud.
Um construction tax fraud is stealing
the future of our roads,
>> [snorts]
>> bridge bridges, and public transit.
Billions of dollars um
meant for infrastructure repairs are
lost every year
because of dishonest con- um contractors
who exploit workers and dodged uh taxes.
Um this April 12th through the 18th, the
Western States Carpenters Local 208 is
taking a stand.
While hardworking taxpayers wait for
potholes to be fixed and highways to be
repaired, corrupt businesses are
pocketing money
that should be feeding or funding these
critical projects.
Strong infrastructure requires fair
labor, honest business, and it's time to
stop tax fraud to ensure roads, bridges,
and transit systems are built the right
way.
The future belongs to those who build
it, and it must be built without tax
fraud.
Sir, are you making accusations that
that's happening in our community?
Yes, sir.
You want to be specific?
Um I've been on projects before where we
found cash pay.
Undocumented workers being paid under
the table.
Okay.
Thanks for bringing that to our
attention.
>> Yeah. No problem.
All right. Thanks, guys. Have a good
evening.
Mr. Miller, you should be able to unmute
yourself.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Mr. Mayor, members of the council, for
the record, Charles Miller. I'm here to
conduct a systemic audit of tonight's
agenda, specifically the structural
misalignment of capital that favors
commercial expansion and administrative
luxury over the physical safety of our
children. Tonight, you are moving to
expand the downtown development district
for Snyder Food, while the DDA's own
amended budget allocates $130,000
for a communications plan
and $45,000
for planters. Concurrently, Ordinance 11
strips $5 million
directly from our
general fund reserves for the Reed
Avenue Corridor. Most audaciously, item
23 asks taxpayers for $22 million to
remodel this building and the
your building, and another $10.4 million
uh for a pool. That is over $37 million
in discretionary spending on tonight's
docket alone. Now, let's
let's look at it the at the veracity
index. Mayor Collins, on February 6th,
you told this community that lead
remediation million-dollar problem. You
used that figure to justify waiting for
federal handouts.
Um
Uh oh, I'm sorry. Um
Uh while 28,000 service lines remain of
unknown material in our water supply
sits in a state of unmanaged liability.
To make matters worse, just minutes ago,
members of this council attempted to put
on the record that our water is safe.
That is a demonstrable falsehood. The
Board of Public Utilities' own data from
September 2025 explicitly shows that
three out of 25 homes tested exceed
tested exceeded the EPA's absolute
maximum action level.
There
There is no
safe level of lead. While you find
millions for vibrant corridors and
office renovations, you are concurrently
moving under item nine to relax the
concentration-based local limits for
lead in our wastewater. You are
literally making it easier for lead to
persist in our environment while you
beautify the surface. Do not tell me the
money isn't there. You proved that pots
of money are fluid when you diverted
$146,300
in ARPA COVID relief funds, money
intended for public health, into a
no-bid surveillance contract for flood
cameras. The general fund is the
ultimate safety net. Using it to
bankroll $5 million for Reed Avenue
while claiming insolvency on lead pipes
is a choice. It is a choice to
prioritize infrastructure vampirism over
public health. Liability is not
segmented. When a child in Cheyenne
suffers cognitive decline, the Manell
liability lawsuit will not just name the
utility board. It will name this city
council for its per-
sistent custom of prioritizing
commercial landscaping over safe
drinking water.
I demand a no on the DDA expansion and
the Reed Avenue appropriation. Table
these items and reallo- reallocate those
general fund reserves to the lead pipe
replacement fund immediately. Fix the
water, then you can talk about the
flowers. Thank you.
>> Mr. Miller, thank you.
Anybody else?
All right, how about from the governing
body? Dr. Aldrich. Uh Mayor Collins,
thank you. I would just like to remind
uh members of the public that we will be
having Council and Coffee in Ward 3 this
Saturday from 9:00 to 11:00 at the
Eastside Dos Bog. Um as our um
regular monthly uh Council and Coffee, I
believe that we are now on number 65 of
these that we've held over the last 5
years, so would welcome um public
comments and thoughts.
Mr. Escobedo.
Mr. Mayor, uh when I got to go tour our
water treatment plant,
it's state of the art. We We have people
from other countries that are coming
here
uh and look
getting advice on what they can do over
over there to make their water fresh and
clean like we have here.
Uh I commend the Board of Public
Utilities for everything they're doing.
And and I know there are some older
homes that we still have to
fix, but they're on it, and they're, you
know, it's going to be expensive, but
we're still getting it done little by
little.
Mr. Moody. Oh. Thank you, Mr. Mayor,
through you. Um I won't be at the
Council and Coffee this uh coming
Saturday. I'll be out of town, but you
can always reach me or my colleagues
from Ward 3. Thank you.
Anybody else?
On the governing body?
I did have one more thing to say. Dr.
Aldrich. Mayor Collins, uh through you.
I'm sorry, I forgot to remind everyone
that this uh Friday night is the uh Fur
Ball on Friday, uh April 17th at Little
America. Um and so I hope to see
everyone there in order to support the
Cheyenne Animal Shelter.
Speaking of Friday night, War is going
to be here, and if you're not going to
go to the
come to Civic Center at 6:30 or 7:30,
Jason? 7:30? 7:30 for a unbelievable
concert, so um
Anybody else in the governing body?
Mr. Seagrave.
Mr. Mayor, pursuant to Wyoming
Statute Section 16-4-405
A7, I move that the governing body meet
in executive session to consider or
receive any information classified as
confidential by law.
Is there a second? Second. Seconded by
Dr. Aldrich.
All those in favor of going into
executive session, please signify by
saying I. I.
Those opposed?
All right, we're going to take a
5-minute break, and then we'll come back
and do this. Mr. Love, hang on just a
second, would you, please?
We are adjourned.
By the way, when we come back, we're
just going to adjourn and go home.
Jason,